Lingjie Jin

TEL: (+86) 15621877997

E-mail: jlj_china@mail.sdu.edu.cn Website: https://lingjie-jin.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I'm a graduate student majoring in energy and power engineering at Shandong University. My research interests are computational fluid dynamics and computer simulation. The goal of my research is to raise our awareness of the fluid.

EDUCATION BACGROUND

Shandong University

Sep 2018 – Expected Mar 2021

Master in Energy and Power Engineering, School of Energy and Power Engineering

• **GPA:** 84.8/100

• Awards: Academic Scholarship (2019)

North China Electric Power University

Sep 2014 – Jun 2018

Bachelor in Energy and Power Engineering, School of Energy and Power Engineering

• **GPA:** 80/100

• Awards: Huamin Charity Foundation Scholarship (2018)

Major Courses: Calculus, Probability Theory, Linear Algebra, Fluid Mechanics, Heat Transfer, Engineering Thermodynamics

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

A simulation model of Fast Cut Back of Power Plant based on MATLAB

May 2020 - Present

- Built a simulation model for the steam heat balance of boiler superheater and high pressure bypass based on MATLAB to studied the main steam pressure and temperature characteristics. It can provide reference for the design of PCV valve and safety valve. (completed)
- Built some simulation models for thermal performance prediction of reheater, deaerator, condenser, small turbine under FCB condition.

Zero Discharge of Desulfurization Wastewater in Laiwu Power Plant

Jul 2019 - Jun 2020

- Assisted my professor to build the pilot test in Shandong Laiwu power plant.
- Studied on the determination of ion content by Atomic Absorption Spectrophotometer.
- Tested the corrosion resistance of different metal materials to desulfurization wastewater.

Development of Power Plant Simulation Software

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019

- Developed the simulation software called CALING by configuration design.
- Built the thermal balance model of the thermal equipment of the power plant by C# language based on the iterative calculation and interpolation calculation.
- Developed a real-time calculation function, and calculated the real-time thermal economy indicators to point out the optimal operating conditions.

Numerical simulation and flow field optimization of spray tower for wet desulfurization

Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

• Built the spray tower model by gambit. Then, studied the influence of the angle and shape of baffle in spray tower on desulfurization efficiency by fluent, next analyzed the influence of flue gas inlet angle on desulfurization efficiency.

SKILLS

- Software: CAD, PROE, ICEM, Fluent, Photoshop, MATLAB
- Programming Languages: C++, C#